Joao Moreira

♀ Exeter. UK

<u>joaosomoreira@gmail.com</u>

+44 7437467596

in/joaosousamoreira

Professional Summary

Software Engineer with seven years of experience programming, designing and delivering reliable, scalable and tested applications, meeting both customer and business needs. Experience with direct to customer and B2B projects. Familiar with working in teams of any size. Experience with collaborating, mentoring and providing direction to colleagues.

Javascript	HTML, Styled Components	PHP
Typescript	CSS Modules, SASS, LESS	Golang
React, React SSR	Webpack, Gulp, Parcel	Python
Redux, Alt.js	Karma, Jest, Jasmine	Java
GraphQL, Apollo Client	TDD / BDD, DDD	Jenkins
Node.js	Micro services architecture	Docker
Angular	Continuous Integration	AWS
Ionic, Cordova	Continuous Deployment	Serverless

Experience

Lead Front-End Developer

Funeral Guide | January 2019 - Present

Lead the Front-End development team (between 3 to 7 people at different points in time) for the Arranger product, a web application built using a React, Redux and GraphQL stack. Also responsible for the building and integration process of the Arranger Front-End using AWS services.

Perform 1-to-1s, conflict resolution, technical mentorship and definition of objectives to all Front-End team members. Provide technical and domain direction for the whole Arranger development team, occasionally performing Scrum Master duties.

Support the entire development team with domain knowledge and occasional Backend work using PHP and Node.js. Delivered a reporting gateway solution as AWS Lambda functions written in Go.

React, ES6, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo Client, PHP, CQRS, Go, Lambda

Senior Front-End Developer

Oneserve Ltd. | October 2017 - December 2018

Lead a small team of developers (between 2 to 3 people) implementing and managing the development lifecycle of a Hybrid Mobile App built using the framework lonic, along with some services from AWS to support it (Cognito, DynamoDB, API Gateway, Lambda), all deployed via serverless as part of the infrastructure. Provide technical direction and some mentorship to team members.

Development of small features for the Core application written in Java.

Typescript, Angular 4, Ionic, Redux, AWS, Java

Joao Moreira

Senior Web Developer

Sound in Theory | August 2016 - October 2017

Developed websites and storefronts using several PHP frameworks. Worked in technology replacement of a back office quoting engine using React with Flux pattern and Gulp for the build process.

Creation of an automated contact form testing framework. Maintained and configured several servers running Apache and Nginx.

React, Flux, FuelPHP, Magento 2, Laravel, Node, JS, Selenium, Gulp, Apache, Nginx

Software Developer

ManyWho Inc. | September 2014 - June 2016

Developed the UI engine using React. Implemented the Front-End of a draw and build tool.

Created a small Python Web Service that converts metadata into Lua code. Designed and implemented workflow solutions using the ManyWho platform and supporting customers on their workflow projects.

React, ES6, Alt.js, Python, Lua

Front-End Developer

blur Group | April 2014 - August 2014

Developed the front-end backbone of platforms and dashboards for customers' use, along with the platforms' respective styling and continuous improvement of user experience.

AngularJS, LESS, jQuery

Software Engineer

Betweien | March 2013 - April 2014

Developed several websites, web and mobile applications, including management of the remote servers where all the applications developed were hosted.

HTML5, Canvas, ¡Query, PHP, Apache

Education

Institute of Engineering of Porto (ISEP), Porto, Portugal BSC Computer Engineering | September 2008 - October 2012

Institute of Engineering of Porto (ISEP), Porto, Portugal iOS Development Course (27 hours) | March 2014 - April 2014